so now let's look at what kinds of
faults can we have we can classify the
faults by cause and we can have a
hardware fault when the hardware of the
system fails to perform as it was
designed to do
we can have design faults for example
softer bugs are design faults and also
some of the hardware design mistakes
such as the famous pentium f div bug
where this fdiv instruction was not
implemented correctly so if you gave it
some combinations of numbers you would
get incorrect results and it was
designed that way
then we have operation faults
for example operator and user mistakes
for example the operator accidentally
tells the system to shut down and now of
course it no longer provides the service
that it's supposed to provide
and then we can have environmental
faults
such as fire
that burns down the system power failure
sabotage of the system all things that
in the environment may cause the system
to have an error or not perform the
service note that these are all faults
some of them don't result in a failure
for example the f div bug doesn't result
in a error or a failure if you never
really use the wrong combination of
numbers for it a softer bug in a rarely
used function
may never result in an actual error
operator faults may not cause a system
to actually have an error for example if
you shut down the system but at this
time for example nobody's trying to use
it
to get service from it it might not be
an actual
failure
and then we can have a fire but if we
protected our system from fire a fire in
the
system room may not actually result in
an error for example we can have a
switch over to another system
power failure can be mitigated so it can
be a fault but may not result in an
error for example if our
battery power supply lasts long enough
to overcome the power failure and so on
so again these are faults
according to their cause any of these
faults might result in errors and
subsequently failures but for all of
them it is possible that we get a fault
but not an error or a failure we can
also classify faults by duration for how
long do we have the fault condition for
example we can have a permanent fold
once we have it
it doesn't get corrected an example of a
permanent fold is when we want to see
what's inside the processor and now the
processor is in four pieces and we don't
know how to put it back together we can
have intermittent faults they last for a
limited duration of time
but they are recurring so it's not like
we get this type of fault and for a
while it causes things to not work fine
but then it just disappears and never
comes back this is something like every
couple of seconds something happens a
good example of intermittent fault is
when we overclock our system it works
fine that crashes then we reboot it it
works fine it crashes and so on so for a
while it works fine but then the same
type of problem recurs and then finally
we have the transient folds which are
when it lasts for a while then just goes
away a transient fault is for example
when an alpha particle hits the chip so
for a while it has all sorts of problems
but then once we reboot it it's no
longer going to have these problems and
they're not going to occur again until
you know much later when something else
happens